TRACEY SMITH

tracey@traceysmith.co.nz traceysmith.co.nz linkedin.com/in/traceymariasmith 021 925 661



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Having worked in the digital world for over fifteen years with progressive experience in digital marketing, product management and customer experience. I've become a passionate advocate for the end user and feel most at home as a champion in converging business and consumer goals when collaborating on projects. Acquainted to being on the front line in the fast paced world of digital media, I've refined my survival skills of translating digital concepts into real tangible products that drive measurable results.

Accomplished at creative development, website/touch point operations, project management and collaborating effectively with stakeholders, vendors and clients through relationship building, influencing and leading. Throughout my career, I've gained vast experience working on large-scale, high- profile initiatives, resulting in a reputation described by colleagues as "gets it done" style. I have led teams managing all aspects of global digital operations including digital marketing, social media, development (website and mobile apps), analytics, content strategy, interface design, usability and online brand protection.

SKILLS

- » Digital Marketing
- » Marketing Automation
- » Email Marketing
- » Product and Content Management
- » Project Management
- » Digital Strategy

- » eCommerce
- » Customer Relationship Management
- » Website Design and Development
- » Search Engine Optimisation
- » Web Analytics and Reporting
- » Social Media Marketing

Relationship Management: build and maintain exceptional internal and external relationships by communicating, influencing, presenting, negotiating and establishing a high degree of credibility and integrity.

Project Management: ability to manage multiple projects while paying attention to detail. Development: experienced in delivering client-focused solutions which solve business problems and customer needs, increasing customer engagement and driving profitable growth.

Lead: lead cross functional teams towards a common goal and build a high performing team. Digital Knowledge: understand online communities and success factors for driving results. Principles and Practice: experience in customer journey and mapping plus implementation of analytics, conversion and optimisation, and analysis.

Commercial Acumen: translate business requirements into strategies.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Agility CIS

Digital Marketer - Contractor

08/2015 - present

Agility CIS provides billing and CRM solutions to utility companies on a global scale. Responsible for leading the development and delivery of marketing campaigns to local and international audiences across multiple channels transforming how customers discover, explore, buy and engage with the brand.

- » Campaign management (content marketing, email, social, SEO/SEM and web)
- » Change Management communicated globally the brand strategy and direction
- » Developed and implemented digital channel strategies and including policies and guidelines
- » Managed multiple digital communications projects working with stakeholders and suppliers
- » Optimised and managed digital communication channels including social media, to continually improve performance and meet business goals continuously leverage best practice and trends inspiring employees and customers with clarity and impact ensuring the marketing investment helps grow the business
- » Lifecycle and reporting monitored and optimised to enhance usability, design, content and conversion rates
- » Lifted brand experience of new and existing customers across digital platforms including optimisation, conversion and best practice
- » Redesigned and launched responsive website including:
 - » wireframes, editorial, graphics through to testing and implementation
 - » focused on customer engagement and experience and enhanced content creation
 - » implemented analytics tracking and reporting giving full visibility into consumer behaviour
 - » improved organic search results boosting traffic and leads
- » Product branding and collateral for six new products creating a cohesive look and feel:
 - » created a logo suite, tag lines/slogans and brand guidelines
 - » brochures and specification sheets (design/layout, copy, imagery, print)

SKY TV

June 2007 – July 2015 09/2014 – 07/2015

SKY GO, IGLOO, NEON TV and MY SKY Video on Demand

Digital Content Production Manager

Ensured world-class digital content was delivered across multiple platforms focusing on customer engagement and experience, while delivering to strategic direction and product management.

- » Managed multiple sites/touchpoints with their distinctly different audiences.
- » Responsible for day-to-day content management for digital tv site SKY GO, NEON TV, MY SKY and IGLOO:
 - » optimising preparation and publishing processes and resolving issues across the four platforms
 - » editorial and promotional planning supporting customer consumption and experience
 - » content delivery and lifecycle
 - » input into company-wide content marketing schedules
 - » ensured each platform breathed its own brand
- » Defining business requirements on new products and systems

Tracey Smith Page 2 of 4

- » Collaborated closely with development and design to align user experience goals and roadmaps to continually launch new features and functionality
- » Worked directly with brand, product, and marketing teams in product launch promotions.
- » Lead, coached, inspired and motivated team of digital content producers (ten direct reports).
- » Delivered projects on time and to budget.
- » Internal and external stakeholder management. Communicated with, persuaded and influenced key internal partners.
- » Monitored and evaluated competitor and industry activity making key recommendations specifically trends and drivers of audience behaviour.
- » Contributed to development of documentation materials.

SKY TV

Digital Channel Manager - SKY GO

09/2010 - 08/2014

SKY GO was SKY's first online TV service allowing subscribers access to on-demand content. The service includes movies, sports and catch-up programming, live streaming channels as well rental content from an extensive library of movies and TV series.

- » Lead team (four direct reports) with responsibilities for the definition, management and execution of:
 - » content marketing and email campaign management
 - » analytics and reporting
 - » online strategy and social media strategy
 - » online brand protection
 - » cross-organisational activities
- » Instrumental in editorial planning, lifecycle and delivery of content to support platform and commercial initiatives.
- » Increased customer engagement through content promotion.
- » Influential in developing common processes for publishing, e-marketing and support issues
- » Built and maintained first-rate relationships with internal and external stakeholders
- » Recommend, implement, track and analyse effectiveness of content
- » Lead and inspired team through coaching and mentoring
- » Actively contributed to platform development and product road maps

SKY TV

Web Producer

06/2007 - 09/2010

It was an exciting and changing environment moving from tradition broadcasting to include online streaming, online acquisition and upgrades plus remote records through customer self-service.

- » Site redesigns (sky.co.nz, skybusiness.co.nz, skyadsales.co.nz, primetv.co.nz) creating consistent user interface and branding
- » Selection of CRM platform and content migration
- » Optimised user experience and strategies to improve subscriber acquisition, conversion, retention and upgrades

» Enhanced, co-ordinated and maintained SKY's website operations.

Tracey Smith Page 3 of 4

- » Upskilled and supported department editors ensuring adherence to publishing processes, editorial and identity standards
- » Supported roll-out of email marketing tool and training
- » Social media activities for SKY TV and Prime TV
- » Intranet planning, implementation, maintenance and enhancement
- » Contractor and vendor management

Bell Gully

Web Application Analyst

April 2004 - June 2007

Bell Gully is a leading New Zealand law firm. The position included maintenance and growth of www.bellgully.com, intranet and due diligence client sites. Dedication to excellence was paramount along with the ability to prioritise and coordinate workflow to meet deadlines.

- » Analysis, development, training, documentation, site maintenance and technical support of client collaboration and due diligence extranet sites.
- » Day to day management of bellygully.com and intranet.
- » Reporting and analysing of internal and external sites.
- » Business requirements analysis and creation of business and technical specifications.
- » Project management.
- » Creation of test plans and analysis testing.
- » Agency and third party vendor management.

Other Positions:

South Africa: Exchange Wise (PTY) Ltd: Webmaster/Designer

England: UBS Private Banking: Webmaster/Designer, Project Office Administrator

Lehman Brothers: Trading Floor Assistant, Equity Research Assistant

Clyde & Co: Events Co-ordinator
Asia: Marco Polo cruise ship

Canada: Imperial Oil, Canada China Business Council, Liquor Control Board of Ontario

NZ: Bulletin Wireless, Skellerup Group Ltd, Winstone Glass, AMP

QUALIFICATIONS

Graduate Diploma in Multimedia

Stakeholder Management

Copy Essentials & Digital Copy Essentials

Keys to Leadership; Part 1 – Understanding Leadership

Managing and Growing your Intranet

Less is More: How the web is forcing us to work smarter, not harder

Skills of Influencing, Assumptions and Communication Styles

Communicating for Maximum Influence

National Certificate in Business: Business Communication

Tracey Smith Page 4 of 4